GREG MILLER

Halifax, NS • (902) 210-5887 • gregpmillr@gmail.com • GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With 7 years of experience, I'm a passionate full-stack developer who strives to exceed expectations when building web systems. My technical proficiency spans backend development, cloud infrastructure, frontend development, technical documentation, and team leadership while thriving in highly-collaborative environments. I look forward to contributing my skills to your team's success!

SKILLS

- Golang, SQL, Javascript, Git, Java, and others
- API Development, Postman
- RDBMS, NoSQL
- Caching methods
- Event-driven systems, PubSub, microservices
- Elasticsearch, Metabase, SSRS, SSIS, SSAS

- React, Nextjs, Gatsbyjs, Laravel
- CI/CD
- Slack
- Docker
- AWS
- Project Management / Jira
- PII / PHI Data Handling

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer

Inkblot Therapy - Toronto, ON

01/2022 - Present

- Oversee Tranquility's development to maintain security, privacy, and access controls.
- Event sourcing audit logs using Elasticsearch.
- Access controls (RBAC, ABAC) using the Casbin Go library.
- Optimization with pprof and Go's data race detector to find race conditions in the PubSub message broker.
- New hire training overhaul for frontend and backend developers, including a different interview strategy, onboarding documentation, and 30-60-90 day plans.
- B2B White labelling using feature flags to control features shown to groups of users.

Full-Stack Developer

ReelData - Halifax, NS

03/2021 - 06/2022

- Simple marketing web application built using Gatsby, Heroku, and AWS.
- Worked with designers for UI/UX incremental development and fixes.
- CI/CD pipelines.

Full-Stack Developer / Lead Developer

Tranquility Online - Halifax, NS

05/2017 - 01/2022

- Oversee frontend, backend development, and cloud infrastructure to a successful acquisition.
- API development, React frontend development, AWS.
- Custom scalable PubSub and chat using web sockets.
- CMS and educational progression system.
- Stripe payment system to create a flexible payment system to handle B2C and B2B customers.
- Plan matching algorithms and handle the development of one.
- Security, PHI, and PII handling with two PIAs and a TRA

Teacher's Assistant & Marker

Dalhousie University - Halifax, NS

01/2017 - 04/2018

- Exercises in Server-side scripting, including PHP, SQL, database design and management, website security, HTTP protocols, REST services, and tools for managing a website application.
- TA and marker for mobile computing, including Android development, design patterns, Volley, and Firebase.
- Marker for assignments and labs.
- Exam proctoring.

Business Intelligence Developer (Co-op)

Emera Energy - Halifax, NS

05/2016 - 09/2017

- Use of SSRS, SSIS, and SSAS to gather business insights for energy traders to make more informed decisions.
- Processed data captured via pipeline sensors and third-party vendors.
- Heavy SQL-based development (~1k lines per day).

Website Developer (Co-op)

NSCC Print Shop - Halifax, NS

02/2015 - 02/2016

- Streamlining the process of old and current print jobs through a Laravel web app.
- MySQL database to collect user information.

EDUCATION

Bachelor: Applied Computer Science

Dalhousie University - Halifax, NS 09/2016 - 05/2020

Diploma: Database Application Development

NSCC Institute of Technology - Halifax, NS 09/2014 - 06/2016